James Weller

78 Byron Street, Hove, East Sussex BN3 5BB ♦ jamesleeweller@gmail.com ♦ 07935 564317

MSc. Graduate with Experience

An ambitious, detail-oriented and uniquely versatile masters graduate, I am eager to pursue a career in research, data analysis or similar and have completed additional training alongside employment in order to achieve this. Organised and tenacious, resourceful and emotionally intelligent, I bring integrity and a positive approach to work, achieving high quality results on time, taking ownership for solving problems and supporting those around me. Having completed an extensive range of training since graduating, I am now ready and eager for my first career entry level role.

♦ Competencies ♦

Data Analysis and Research: Data preparation and cleansing, data exploration and manipulation, data visualisations, creating dashboards and reports. Toolset includes Python, R, SQL and Excel. Complementary skills include knowledge of statistics and experience of qualitative and quantitative research.

Communicating with clarity and influence: Able to communicate technical information clearly to others and adapt my style to suit any given audience, I have been a tutor at University to undergraduates, communicated to the general public in customer oriented roles and supported the elderly in learning IT. Overall, I have strong client facing skills.

Team work and leadership: A supportive, upbeat and collaborative team member with genuine commitment towards achieving a shared objective, I have over 4 years' experience working as part of a team. At University I was a senior Peer Assisted Learning Leader running weekly sessions to help new students during their first year and coached other leaders in how to best support students.

Problem solving and organisation: With tangible enthusiasm for problem solving and driving improvements, I balance a logical approach with creativity to unravel and understand complexities before finding solutions. This approach, in tandem with solid planning and organisation skills, has played a key part in my ability to learn quickly and achieve the highest academic grades.

Education & Training *

Memberships: Institute of Leadership & Management (ILM)

2019 – 2019: Digital Marketing – Future Learn / Google Analytics – Google

2018 – 2019: <u>DataCamp Training</u>

Over 15 training courses completed including:

Data Scientist with Python Track
Data Scientist with R Track

Interactive Data Visualisation with Bokeh

Joining Data in PostgreSQL Network Analysis in Python Python Data Science Toolbox

2016 – 2017: University of Bedfordshire

Master of Science (M.Sc.) Forensic Psychology – Distinction

Including Advanced Research Methods

*Award: University of Bedfordshire Jubilee Scholarship Award for Post-Graduate studies

2013 – 2016: <u>University of Bedfordshire</u>

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) Psychology and Criminal Behaviour – FIRST

Including Research Methods and Data Analysis

2009 – 2012: A levels x 4: Psychology, Archaeology, Finance and Environmental Studies

*Awards: IP Student of the Year Award and 3 Commendations

GCSEs x 8: including Mathematics, Sciences and English

Employment Experience *

Alongside academic studies, I have worked for the following employers developing skills in teamwork, communication, customer service and organisation.

2016 – Present: **Design Asylum**

- > Managing stock levels for this fast-moving fashion retailer which distributes products internationally
- > Processing orders accurately and in line with standard operating procedures
- > Overseeing goods inward, checking the integrity of stock delivered and meeting customers' deadlines

2007 – 2014: Mechanical Improver, Self-employed

- > Working with steel, plastic and copper piping
- > Installing new mechanical systems for clients in accordance with schematics
- > Adhering to strict health and safety standards and meeting clients' deadlines and order specifications

2007 – 2007: **Telegen**

> A telesales role involving communicating to large volumes of customers on the phone, responding to a broad range of queries and providing advice and assistance to meet their needs

2002 – 2006: **Endeva**

- > Installing electrical equipment, white and brown goods within customers' homes
- > Assisting the driver with planning delivery routes and completing paper work associated with delivery
- > Communicating to customers, demonstrating usage of the product and responding to questions

♦ Mentoring & Teaching Experience ◆

2016 – 2016: **University of Bedfordshire – Teaching Assistant**

- > Leading classroom discussion and debates, planning and running activities in tutorials
- > Creating focused learning environments and developing knowledge within undergraduate students

2014 – 2016: University of Bedfordshire – Senior Peer Assisted Learning (PAL) Leader

- > Assisting new university students in confidently transitioning from home to university life
- > Providing information, practical support and mentoring where needed
- > Supporting junior Peer Leaders in developing the skills needed to help students
- * Awards: PAL Leader Award 2016, PAL Special Leader Commendation (2015 & 2016)

2012 – 2012: **AGE UK – IT Assistant**

> Teaching users basic IT skills including use of Email, Microsoft Word and Excel

Areas of Technical Skill, Knowledge and Expertise

Statistical, Data Analysis and Programming:

Data Analysis in Python (Pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, scikit-learn, scipy and numpy)

Quantitative & Qualitative Research Method

IBM SPSS (5 years+ experience)

Jupyter Notebook

SAS, SQL, HTML & CSS (experience)

R Statistical Programming (ggplot2, dplyr, psych and car)

Technical Skills: MS Office and Google Office **Operating Systems:** Windows, OSX and Linux

Additional Details *

Portfolio: Examples of data analysis and research work: https://jameslweller.github.io/Portfolio.html

References: If selected, details of references can be provided at interview.